commercepc.com 2010-03-23

# Metro Bank Serving Central PA

## Privacy and Security

Strong protection for your information

### Important Information About Your Privacy

This notice provides detail about the information we collect and disclose, and explains how we handle privacy as it relates to you and your accounts.

### Our Commitment To You

We want you to know that your relationship with us is treated with the confidentiality that you expect and deserve. Trust, privacy and confidentiality are the guiding principles upon which Metro Bank's relationship with you is built. Because we are committed to serving the needs of our customers, we will take all reasonable steps to protect the privacy of their relationship with us.

### Protecting Customer Information

Access to your personal information is limited to those Metro Bank employees who need to know the information to provide products and services to you. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect your **non-public information**.

### What You Can Do To Protect Your Financial Information

  * Routinely review and reconcile your account statements.
  * If you become aware of incorrect information either in our records or as reported by Metro Bank, please notify us at 1-888-937-0004 and we will promptly make the necessary corrections.
  * Safeguard and protect your account records and other information pertaining to your relationship with Metro Bank.
  * Do not disclose your confidential non-public information (personal identification number, social security number, account numbers, etc.) to unknown persons.

Remember that cellular, mobile and cordless phones are not secure. Neither is electronic mail (e-mail); regard it as you would a postcard. 

### Crime Prevention

Metro Bank takes crime prevention very seriously. For your convenience, the links below go to practical, expert advice.

  * Avoid Identity Theft & Online Fraud (Source: Metro Bank)
  * [How to Guard Against Identity Theft](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/microsites/idtheft) (Source: Federal Trade Commission)
  * [Advice for Safe Online Shopping](http://www.fdic.gov/consumers/consumer/news/cnsum01/cvrstry.html) (Source: Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation)
  * ATM Safety Tips (Source: Metro Bank)

### Important Information About Procedures for Opening a New Account

To help the government fight the funding of terrorism and money laundering activities, Federal law requires all financial institutions to obtain, verify, and record information that identifies each person who opens an account. What this means for you: When you open an account, we will ask for your name, address, date of birth, and other information that will allow us to identify you. We may also ask you to send a copy of your driver's license or other identifying documents.

### Information We Collect

We collect **non-public, personal** information about you to help serve your financial needs, provide customer service, offer new products or services, and fulfill legal and regulatory requirements. These types of **non-public, personal** information may include:

  * Information we received from you on loan applications or other forms.
  * Information about your transactions with Metro Bank or others.
  * Information from outside companies or third parties, such as credit bureaus, motor vehicle reports and demographic information.

We collect only the information necessary to deliver quality products and services to our customers.

### Information We Share

We are permitted by law to share **non-public information** about you with outside companies or **non-affiliated, third parties** that participate with us in supplying products and services to you, such as check printers. We are permitted, or required, by law to share your information with credit bureaus and government entities in responding to subpoenas and other legal processes, as well as those companies with whom you have requested us to share information.

These **non-affiliated, third party** companies are not permitted to use your information for any purposes other than the services intended. We will share your information with these companies only if they agree to treat it confidentially.

The type of information we may share is:

  * Information we receive from you on loan applications or other forms, such as name, address, social security number, assets and income.
  * Information about transactions with Metro Bank, such as account balances and payment history.

We may also disclose information we have about you to companies with whom we have joint marketing agreements or who provide marketing services on our behalf. We may share information about you with another financial institution to jointly offer financial services to you.

**We do not sell, rent or otherwise provide customer information to outside companies so they can market non-financial services to you.**

Metro Bank may make a decision to sell a particular line of business (for example, mortgage servicing rights). Usually, an integral part of that business is its customer database. Metro Bank reserves the right, in circumstances such as these, to transfer ownership of such customer databases to the purchaser. We do not share any **non-public, personal** information about our customers or former customers to anyone, except as permitted by law. 

### Online Protection

All of our Internet forms and pages with customer or other sensitive information are protected by data-encryption technology. Encryption is a procedure for turning plain text or other information into an unrecognizable pattern of data requiring a unique key to open or "decode" the formula. The unbroken key or closed lock on your screen indicates that the connection is secure.

Although we provide data encryption and other types of protection to maintain the security of our customers' information, there are certain security, corruption, transmission error and access-availability risks associated with using open networks such as the Internet. Should you decide at any time that you prefer not to use our online services, please visit any store or call us at 1-888-937-0004. 

### How We Handle E-Mail

Our website does not require you to disclose any personal identifying information. If, however, you choose to contact us via e-mail, please keep in mind that your e-mail address, and any other information your e-mail header shows about you, such as your name or organization, will be revealed to us in the e-mail. We pledge, however, that when you communicate with us via e-mail, we will use that information only to respond to the inquiry, provide accurate information to any questions, and in certain instances, assist in the resetting of passwords. Your e-mail address will not be sold, nor will it be shared with others outside of Metro Bank unless we are compelled to do so by law. 

We want to be very clear: we will not obtain personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. 

### About "Cookies"

To provide better service and a more effective website, we use "cookies" as part of our interaction with your browser. A "cookie" is a small, text file placed on your hard drive by our webpage server. These cookies do not collect personally identifiable information, and we do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information to determine who you are or your e-mail address.

Cookies are commonly used on websites and do not harm your system. By configuring your preference or options in your browser, you determine if and how a cookie will be accepted. We use cookies to determine if you have previously visited our website and for a number of administration purposes. Third-party sites may also use cookies. 

### No Data "Capture" With Planning Tools

There are planning tools throughout the site to help you make the financial decisions that are right for you in the privacy of your home. We encourage you to try all of your "what-if" scenarios as often as you like. Examples include the home loan, auto loan and mortgage payment calculators and the IRA eligibility guides.

When you use various planning tools on our website, the calculation run on your computer or our server will not include the capture of your personal information. 

### Accuracy of Information

If you believe we have reported inaccurate information about your account to any consumer-reporting agency, please let us know in writing. Be sure to include your complete name, current address, Social Security Number, telephone number, account number, type of account, specific item of dispute, and the reason you believe the information is wrong. Please notify us and we will make the necessary corrections promptly. Send your notice to:

Metro Bank  
Attn: Customer Service Department  
3801 Paxton Street  
Harrisburg, PA 17111
